hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is Jeremy
Krakowski we haven't met yet I help
coaches trainers authors and mentors
scale their businesses to six seven and
even eight Figures it's over 10 million
dollars plus we've built multiple
eight-figure coaching businesses over
the years and I want to help you get
more clients make more money than you
ever imagined and have the life that
you've always dreamed of by impacting
people and and being able to do all the
things that you want to do
and that's what this podcast is for and
today I want to talk about how to handle
the negative comments you get on social
media how to professionally handle
trolls online how to handle the negative
feedback that we get from people how to
stay positive in the face of negativity
and the truth is this if you're a coach
if you're a trainer if you're a mentor
you're gonna have
the Cesspool the the the the potty tank
the the septic tank of the world
slinging crap at you on a regular basis
saying all of this negativity there's no
way to avoid it there's no way to stop
it there's no way to limit it and
there's nothing that you can do to
prevent it
and so a listen if you're somebody that
experienced trauma you experienced a lot
of bullying or narcissist abuse or this
in your life this may be hard for you to
hear when you want to go out there and
build a business online because the
people who abused you are going to be
out there saying things that are going
to trigger you and hurt you this is why
I tell people you need to commit to
personal development working on the
stuff that hurts you so that you can
develop mental toughness have stronger
mental performance and make your mental
health be an important priority for you
so that no matter who comes at you you
don't worry about it you don't worry
about the negativity you don't worry
about them assuming bad things about you
and listen
as a coach as a trainer there's a lot of
scammers that are out there people are
going to project onto you that you are
one of those bad horrible things that
they don't like
that's part of it no matter how good you
are no matter how much Great Value you
do no matter how honest or much
Integrity you have you're gonna have
these haters you're gonna have these
trolls you're gonna have these people
that are gonna assume the worst and are
going to be convinced of the worst and
make up a story in their head that's
fabricated that's not true that it has
no basis in reality about you because it
validates their story inside of them
okay so how do you handle this well the
first step really is to learn to develop
your mental toughness your mental
strength and for me I used to really shy
away I used to sweat bullets based off
of people saying negative things about
me assuming that I did wrong things and
I had a lot of people that would come at
me accusing me of all this terrible
stuff that I was quote unquote doing
that I wasn't really doing at all in my
business and it made me shrink back it
made me take my message and make it very
small
and maybe take some of the best parts of
my message and not even say them to
people because I was afraid of the
feedback that I would get from people
the negativity that would come my way
and and I had to work through that and I
had to commit through that and and I
ended up working with a therapist at
betterhelp.com to help me go through
that before I could afford that I used a
website called sevencups.com it's the
number seven and then cups and there's
counselors on there that you can work
with that can help you work through to
develop the mental toughness to develop
the mental stability to do this there's
books that you can read there's ways
that you can do this and here's one of
the best things is boundaries
learning whose opinions to actually
worry about I'm going to draw this on
the Whiteboard here if you're somebody
that's watching on the video you're
going to see this so I'm drawing a big
circle right here this is everybody in
the world oh and they got lots of
opinions about you here's you in the
center okay
and here's a little tiny Circle that's
drawn around you in the center these are
your close Inner Circle I'm talking less
than five people
a lot of you think your inner circle is
like 50 to 100 people no it's less than
five people
less than five people in your life that
you care about what they think about you
that you take their opinions to Heart
that you filter through and you get to
choose and decide that list
don't ever let anybody decide that for
you or they will manipulate and weasel
themselves into your life in a place of
authority in your life I allowed people
to do that I regret it and I had to move
away from those people and move them out
to the Outer Circle of people these are
people that you talk to
on a regular basis you and you don't
have to agree agree with it you don't
even have to agree with Who's In Your
Inner Circle by the way we got to get
rid of this idea in our lives that we
gotta agree with everybody
I don't agree with half the people that
are in my inner circle
let alone the ones that I talk to on a
regular basis
but I don't have to take on their
opinions about me
I don't have to let their opinions about
me affect me and there's a whole bunch
of nuances as to why that is I was
raised that anybody's opinion was truth
about me
and so I filtered that in my life and I
anybody whatever they thought about me I
took on as my reality and I was living
like
schizophrenically not really like
clinically diagnosed schizophrenic but
like my brain was all these different
things that people thought about me all
the time
and I didn't respect my own opinions
about me
I didn't have the self-esteem inside of
me to respect what I thought about me
I thought it was prideful I thought it
was arrogant I thought it was a bad
thing a selfish thing and that was the
biggest lie that I I was ever taught
growing up and a lot of us have that and
a lot of us worry about the negativity
that people sling at us because we have
that framework of that standard because
we want to respect other people because
I want to we want to respect their
opinions listen you can respect
somebody's right to sling crap at you
they have the right to do that listen if
somebody's throwing negativity at you
they have a right to do that and I'm
going to draw another circle out here
these are people that interact with you
but you don't have to interact back with
them
and they don't need to be positive or
negative good or bad
but you're going to find listen I have
made a choice where I only ever interact
with positive people
I'm in a choice where I literally don't
even respond back to somebody who swings
negativity at me
it's not worth it
it's not worth it I used to feel like I
had to have give an account to everybody
there's a Bible verse I twisted give an
account for the hope that's with you
know proved what workmen are not a
like this idea that I had to give an
account to everybody and explain myself
and defend myself to everybody as soon
as you stop defending yourself to
anybody and you don't even pay like and
you learn that their opinions don't
matter
and you and you learn to strengthen your
mind to where you don't worry about what
everybody thinks about you that you
don't worry about the opinions that
people will sling at you
you become somebody that can build a
business successfully
how do you handle the trolls I delete
them
I delete their comments sometimes if
it's if it is bothering me because
here's the thing I don't respond but
I'll read it and it will bother me
sometimes
I'd be lying if I said it didn't
and then I look up well that's an area
that I need to grow in
if it's bothering me that much it's an
area that I need to I write it down in
my notepad on my phone
and I might go talk about it with my
therapist or I'll
talk to my wife about it
but I don't want to bring the negativity
into the relationship with my wife by
telling her all the stuff that they're
telling me
I used to do that and it really put a
strain on our marriage on our
relationship I started telling all my
friends and my family all the negativity
that people were bringing at me
and so all of my conversations were
talking about all the negativity that
people were slinging at me and there was
no positivity in my relationship because
I was constantly talking about all the
stuff that other people were doing
and so I had to find somebody that was
my therapist that I could talk with
about this stuff and work through these
triggers somebody that that was that is
a confidant maybe one person in your
life it doesn't have to be a therapist
my wife is this for for for
a friend of hers and she's able to bring
the negative stuff to her life but it's
kind of you know like a form of therapy
you might have that one friend where
your friendship is based on that that's
okay
but don't make it all your friends don't
make it all your family I'd recommend
not making it your spouse
definitely not
to talk about all the negativity is what
I'm eating but talk about the positivity
talk about the exciting stuff start
changing your language and your focus
and what you start talking about when
you start looking at and what you start
saying and how you start interacting
with people and do so from a positive
light and a positive perspective and
some instead of somebody that is
complaining all the time instead of
somebody that is that is is constantly
worried and stressed out and upset all
the time instead focus on all the good
stuff that you want in the world
and create boundaries on who you're
actually going to pay attention to and
so I delete the negative people I delete
them I block them from my social media I
don't even respond to them
that's how I handle it
and I realize that those people are
hurting those people are slinging their
crap at me because they're hurting
inside because they're sad they're sad
about themselves they're sad about what
they're going through they're they're
people that don't believe in themselves
they find Satisfaction by hurling these
horrible negative opinions on us and it
has nothing to do with me
it has nothing to do with who I am
and when you know your worth when you
know who you are when you believe in
yourself for me as a Christian as a
believer in Jesus
my worth comes from my relationship with
Christ
my worth comes from my faith
my worth comes from what I know that God
says about me and God says that he is
pleased with me
he looks down at me and says
that I'm incredible and amazing and that
I'm worthy of love and connection
and so I don't worry about what other
people think when I live in Integrity
when I walk out in integrity
and and hey here's the thing here's the
other thing I want to challenge you with
I'm going to challenge you here now okay
if you're somebody who doesn't keep your
promises
if you're somebody that's constantly
backbiting criticizing if you're
somebody that's doing things that maybe
you know you shouldn't do
that's where the worry can sometimes
come from
I'm not saying that the worry comes from
that you are doing something like that
I'm saying if you are here's the
difference if you're somebody that has
experienced trauma pain
you the negativity that that people hurl
at you
is is is is is gonna impact you whether
you did something wrong or not
but if you're some and you know hey
maybe I need to fix this in my life
maybe I need to be more accountable
start having that accountability in your
life
start inviting that accountability find
a mentor find a coach find somebody that
can keep you accountable and on track to
actually do what you say you're going to
do start trusting
the promises that you make to yourself
start believing the things that you say
that you're going to do
start doing the things that you've been
putting off
when you're an active person you no
longer become worried when anybody
thinks about you one of the biggest
reasons why we worry about the
negativity from other people is because
we're just sitting around focused so
much on other people instead of what we
need to do in our lives and so I'm going
to challenge you with that I'm
one of the best ways to deal with
negativity is to put blinders on and
focus on what you're building
and not worry about what other people
think about you an active man and woman
doesn't have time to worry about those
haters
one of the biggest reasons why we end up
doing that is because we're too focused
on overthinking over stressing out what
happens is our brains get so focused on
ruminating over how everything can go
wrong we're ruminating over all the
stuff that we should be doing all the
things that we're not doing and instead
if we actually went out there and just
started doing those things our Focus
would change
three
another thing could be your diet if
you're eating a lot of sugar
if you're eating a lot of negative food
if you're not getting enough sleep
if you're not taking care of yourself
you're not going to expect other people
to take care of you and so that's why
self-care is so important
and self-care isn't just rest or video
games or or eating a donut because you
want to what I'm talking about when I
talk about self-care is is actually
taking care of your body actually taking
care of your life actually taking care
of your home
and and doing those things because you
want to not because you think well I
should be doing them and this will
change your life when you start making
yourself a priority when you start doing
what you want to do because you want to
do it and you're not worried about
what other people think about you you
don't got time for any of those haters
that are out there any of that
negativity because you know you got a
vision you're a person a man or a woman
that has a vision for where you're going
in your life
and nothing can stop you
some good reading for some of you check
out the meditations of Marcus Aurelius
as well
the meditations of Marcus Aurelius is
one of my favorite
things that I recommend people check out
I I listen to them I read them there's
some videos on YouTube that you can find
just type in meditations of Marcus
Aurelius
There's a summary that I really like I
posted on my social media
meditation to Marcus Aurelius just like
the 22 stoic principles
or this I'm actually gonna just go down
the list
what to do when you encounter unkindness
everything depends on how you interpret
it how you should sit
how to stay mindful how to be deliberate
how to not run away from Fear how to be
open to correction how to have
self-respect how to avoid complaining
what to do in the face of adversity
Marcus Aurelius was an emperor
in ancient Rome and and his diary was
called the meditations of Marcus
Aurelius and and and and he wrote down
for his own personal thoughts
this and they're applicable today to our
own life and so check them out they're
free as well you can find them anywhere
you can find a ton of videos on YouTube
about them
they're powerful it's powerful ancient
wisdom of stoicism
that can help you become stronger
mentally that can help you not be so
fearful of what everybody thinks about
you that can help strengthen you to have
confidence as a man or woman that knows
where they're going in their life
okay this is one of the videos that that
I that I found that I at least um
like when I look it up if you're
watching the YouTube version is the
first one that comes up on YouTube
summary right here
there's a number of people that talk
about it
about being yourself about
self-discipline
a lot of the personal development
training that's out there this is the
one of the one of the earliest known
personal development
sort of texts that are out there that
people have been studying through years
and years and years that can help you
become a more powerful person okay so
check those out
I found that was really helpful in my
life I think you will as well
listen if this has helped you if you're
somebody that's listening to this
podcast share it with somebody I'd love
for this to impact other people as well
if they're dealing with haters trolls
fearing being canceled on the internet
we live in the world now where the crowd
does have some kind of power where
people can end up shutting us down but
that's not something you need to worry
about especially when you're just
getting started as a business owner as a
coach
just ignore it just put blinders on
ignore what people think about you be
yourself do the things that you know
that you need to do that are best for
you that are best for you and your
family and live your life with
confidence
that's why boundaries are so key who do
you let Into Your Inner Circle who do
you actually care about their opinions
of
and really don't care about what anybody
else thinks about you that's the best
thing to do my life got better when I
stopped worrying what anybody else
thinks or says
I just started doing what I want to do
more often
I used to think that was a bad thing
I just think that that was selfish so
that made me a bad person
and I used to have people accuse me of
that too
those aren't people that are meant to be
in my life they're not meant to be in
your life
I'm not talking about going out there
intentionally abusing people taking
advantage of them manipulating them for
personal gain please hear me out don't
do that I don't support that and I don't
live my life that way
but when you make yourself a priority
and you make your mental performance a
priority and you make
feeling your best and and operating from
your best state of mind to priority
and you stop worrying about other people
and what they think and what they say
that you should be doing and you stop
letting the should Do's that people
project on you in the world control your
life and you stop taking what other
people say well you should be doing this
or you should be doing that and you let
them control you
you become a more powerful person that
can go out there and impact the world on
a greater level
if you're a coach if you're a trainer if
you're a mentor if you're a teacher if
you're a course grader and you want to
know how to make more money doing that
that's what I cook people on how to do I
do live virtual events every single
month where I show you I give you the
best content the formula that you need
to be successful we're in the middle of
a virtual event right now you might be
able to look at my YouTube channel and
find them and go watch through those
usually the recordings are taken down
within a week after those you can
purchase them later for a low fee of
usually about 47 to 97 bucks
I'd love to work with you I'd love to
help you I'd love to help you make more
money in your life your business
but it's going to take some commitment
to mental toughness to do so
again share this episode with somebody
if you know that's impacted you and you
think it will impact somebody else's
life let them know about it let them
know about the podcast
grow your life everybody we'll talk soon
have a good one